XIAOWEI LIU

x.liu7@universityofgalway.ie | +353(87)4856803

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Chinese automotive postgraduate with 3 years' experience in researching battery management system and 1.8-year experience in Electric Vehicle OEM's R&D department. Now taking a software postgraduate course in NUIG, keen to find an internship in new energy&&technical field.

EDUCATION

2023.09-Now Master of Software Design & Development, NUIG, Galway, Ireland

• Subjects include: Programming, Algorithms & Logical, Databases, etc.

2018.09-2021.06 Master of Vehicle Engineer, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China

- Average Score: 84.16/100
- Final Year Project: Performance Prediction and Management of Electric Vehicle Lithium-ion Power Battery Packs
- Other Projects: LFP Cell SOX Algorithm Project Based on Dynamic Self-adaptive Model NMC Cell Power Prediction Algorithm
- Subjects include: New Energy Vehicle and Power Engineering, Automotive Engineering, etc.

2014.09-2018.06 Bachelor of Mechanical Engineer, Jilin University, Jilin, China

- Average Score: 76.32/100
- Final Year Project: Milling machine drive system design
- Subjects include: Engineering Fundamental, Fundamental of Control in Mechanical Engineering, etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021.11-2023.08 Battery Strategy Engineer, Shanghai Automotive Industry Co., Ltd, Shanghai, China

- To develop SOX algorithm of BMS application software, including Model improvement/Code generation/HIL test and etc. Mainly using Matlab/Simulink/Polyspace.
- To support data collection, mainly using Vector's CAN devices to record CAN/CANFD data on the test car. Sometimes using INCA to observe control inner parameters.
- To manage the BMS's relating HMI requirement such as energy and battery heating control display on the entertainment and instrument screen of the Morris Garages. Roewe. Rising Auto and IM Auto's EV.
- To research advanced frames to evaluate battery pack's inconsistency, prepare summary paper review slides and participate in those new model integration.

2021.07-2021.11 Supplier Quality Engineer, General Motor, Shanghai, China

 To communicate with different departments such manufacture, engineer quality and R&D to handle automotive part quality issues in short time, to make sure that those problems not delay the factory's production rhythm.

2020.07-2020.08 Technical Research Intern, Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd, Shanghai, China

- To propose an open circuit voltage prediction method for the calibration of the mobile phone remaining power and wrote the technical document.
- To help the team built the fault prediction models based on deep learning algorithm to determined mobile phone fault characteristics, such as label mobile phone user data and adjust model inner parameters.

2018.09-2019.12 Battery Lab Intern, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China

- To manage daily operation plan of the laboratory, such as shift arrangement, test equipment maintenance, battery experiment management, etc.
- To introduce new students about the battery laboratory, and conduct teaching slides and demonstration videos of experimental equipment.

SKILLS PROFILE

Computer skills:

- Microsoft Office(proficient)
- Matlab(proficient)
- Simulink(proficient)
- Java(experienced)
- Python(experienced)
- CANoe(experienced)
- CAPL(experienced)
- CATIA(experienced)
- CAD(experienced)

Language skills:

- English(conversational)
- Mandarin(conversational)

ACHIEVEMENTS

 Chinese patent: XIONG Rui, DUAN Yanzhou, LIU Xiaowei. Battery capacity estimation method.201911267620.0.2019.12.11

INTERESTS/HOBBIES

Soccer: won the runner-up of the Northeast China University Football League in 2017, supporter of Dortmund F.C.

REFEREES

Name: Zhang Jianhai

Job title: Associate Professor Address: Jilin University, China Phone number: +8613596033966

Email: jianhaizhang@jlu.edu.cn

Name: He Jialong

Job title: Associate Professor Address: Jilin University, China Phone number: +8618943161591

Email: hejl@jlu.edu.cn

Name: Peng Min

Job title: Senior Battery Engineer

Address: Shanghai Automotive Industry Co., Ltd, Shanghai, China

Phone number: +8617621790455 Email: pengmin4job@163.com